Finding aid for the Collection of Political Cartoons and Caricatures, 18th-20th Century LSC.2119
UCLA Library Special Collections
A Collection of Political Cartoons and Caricatures
18th-20th century
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.2119
2 Linear Feet (1 box)
Collection of Political cartoons and caricatures from various countries, notably England and Egypt.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
The source of the collection is unknown.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9975427743606533
Biography/History
Collection of Political cartoons and caricatures from various countries, notably England and Egypt. The source of the collection is unknown.
Scope and Content
Political cartoons appearing in The Cairo Punch, Harper's Weekly, New York Herald, The Evening Mail, The Graphic and unidentified publications.
Organization and Arrangement
Listed by title.
- Colombia's New Suitors [by C.G. Bush. Appeared in a New York newspaper]., 1898 September 25 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 1)
- The New Member Of The Orchestra [by M. Nelan? Appeared in The New York Herald]., 1898 August 28 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 2)
- Le Reveil Du Lion Par Gill., 187? (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 3)
- And The Hearst Of 1901 Is The Candidate Of To-Day [appeared in The Evening Mail]., 1906 November 2 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 4)
- The Tang, Or Grave Impropriety., 1913 December (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 5)
- [WWI military leaders slipping off a raft, by Stanger Pritchard]., 1918 December 25 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 6)
- [WWI military leaders hanging from nooses, by Stanger Pritchard]., undated (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 7)
- Nemesis [by Henrietta Rae. Appeared in The Graphic]., 1918 December 14 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 8)
- [WWI depiction of a military leader, pictured with quote from King Richard III, Act V. Sc. 3]., undated (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 9)
- Victory And Death [appeared in Harper's Weekly]., 1865 June 10 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 10)
- The Bengal Levee [published by J. Gillray and H. Humphrey]; The Slough of Despond [published by H. Humphrey]; Tom Paine's Nightly Pest [published by H. Humphrey]., 1792; 1793 January 2; undated (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 11)
- A Barber's Shop in Assize Time [by James Gillray]., 1811 January 9 (published 1818 May 15) (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 12)
- The Rake's Progress at the University No. 1 [published by H. Humphrey]; The Rake's Progress at the University No. 2 [published by H. Humphrey]; Morning Promenade upon the Cliff, Brighton [published by H. Humphrey]., 1806 October 22; 1806 October 2; 1806 January 24 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 13)
- Venus a la Cozuelle or the Swan-sea Venus [published by H. Humphrey]; Theatrical Mendicants relieved, "a Begging we will go!" a scene from Covent Garden Theatre after the Conflagration [published by H. Humphrey]; Famer Giles and his Wife sh[o]wing off their daughter Betty to their Neighbours on her return from School [published by H. Humphrey]., 1809 March 28; 1809 January 15; 1809 January 1 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 14)
- Siege De La Colonne De Pompée [published by H. Humphrey]; The Apotheosis of Hoche [published by H. Humphrey]., 1799 March 6; 1798 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 15)
- The Pigs Possessed or the Broad bottomed Litter running headlong into a/y Sea of Perdition [published by H. Humphrey]; a Kick at the Broad Bottoms! i.e. Emancipation of "All the Talents," [published by H. Humphrey]; Political Mathematician's Shaking the Broad bottomed Hemispheres [published by H. Humphrey]., 1807 April 18; 1807 March 23; 1807 January 9 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 16)
- Confederated Coalition or The Giants Storming Heaven with the Gods alarmed for their everlasting abodes [published by H. Humphrey]; Middlesex-Election, 1804 "a Long-Pull, a Strong-Pull, and a Pull-All-together," [published by H. Humphrey]., 1804 May 1; 1804 August 7 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 17)
- Shakespeare Sacrificed or The Offering to Avarice [published by H. Humphrey]; The Monster broke loose [crossed out] a peep into the Shakespeare Gallery [published by H. Humphrey]; Bombardian, Conferring upon State Affairs with one in Office., 1789 June 20; 1791 April 26; undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 18)
- He steers his flight Aloft, incumbent on the dusky air That felt unusual weight [published by H. Humphrey]., 1810 August 8 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 19)
- Titanus Redivivus or The Seven Wise Men consulting the new Venetian Oracle, a scene in e/y Academic Grove [published by H. Humphrey]; Homer singing his Verses to the Greeks [published by H. Humphrey]; The Salute [published by H. Humphrey]., 1797 November 2; 1797 June 16; 1797 July 10 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 20)
- A March to the Bank [published by S. W. Fores]; Monstrous Craws at a New Coalition Feast [published by S. W. Fores]., 1787 August 22; 1787 May 29 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 21)
- Blood on Thunder fording the Red Sea [published by S. W. Fores]; The Political Baditti assailing the Savior of India [published by Will Holland]; Wife and no Wife or A trip to the Continent [published by Will Holland]., 1788 March 1; undated; 175(?) March 27 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 22)
- Le Garde Rural Par Gill., 187(?) (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 23)
- Du Rhenm Bleibst Deutscm Wie Meine Brust! Lieb Vaterland [appeared in Harper's Weekly]., 1871 April 15 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 24)
- A new way to pay the National Debt [published by Will Holland]; Honi Soit Qui Mal Y Pense [published by I. Jarvis Richmond Buildings]; Anticipation or the approaching fate of the French Commercial Treaty [published by W. Holland]., 1786 April 21; undated; undated (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 25)
- Ancient Music [published by S. W. Fores]; A noble Lord, on an approaching Peace too busy to attend to the Expenditure of a Million of the Public Money [by R. Phillips]; The Board of Controul or the Blessings of a Scotch Dictator [by R. Phillips]., 1787 May 10; 1787 March 12; 1787 March 20 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 26)
- The Bridal Night [published by H. Humphrey]; Parliamentary Reform or Opposition Rats learning the House they had Undermined [published by H. Humphrey]; LeBaiser a la Wirtembourg [published by H. Humphrey]., 1797 May 18; 1797 May 28; 1797 April 15 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 27)
- Lieu(t) Gover(r) Gall Stone, inspired by Alector or The Birth of Minerva [published by H. Humphrey, by James Gillray]; Taming of the Shrew: Katharine and Petruchio The Modern Quiscotte or what you will [published by S. W. Fores]; The Impeachment or The Father of the Gang turn[e]d King's Evidence [published by S. W. Fores]., 1790 February 15; 1791 April 20; 1791 May (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 28)
- The Morning after Marriage or A scene on the Continent [published by W. Holland]; Questions and Commands or The Mistaken Road to He_r_f_rd, a Sunday Evening's Amusement [published by H. Humphrey]; The Westminster Hunt [published by S. W. Fores]., 1788 April 5; 1788 February 11; 1788 April 27 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 29)
- La Marseillaise Par Gill., undated (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 30)
- The Tammany Tiger Loose [appeared in Harper's Weekly]., undated (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 31)
- [Woman crying over Lincoln's casket, appeared in Harper's Weekly]., undated (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 32)
- The Egyptians., 1908 May (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 33)
- [Various countries gathered around a depiction of Turkey]., 1908 March (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 34)
- International Race., 1908 April (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 35)
- [Beast depicting Panislamism attacking other countries]., 1908 June (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 36)
- [France toasting John Bull over the dead bodies of Egypt and Morocco with Casa Blanca burning in the background]., 1908 February (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 37)
- [England welcoming passengers of a boat]., 1908 June (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 38)
- [Depiction of Japan, having defeated China and Russia, challenging Uncle Sam to a fight]., 1908 February (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 39)
- [Depiction of Egypt addressing John Bull and various other countries]., 1908 March (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 40)
- [France conquering Morocco who begs for help from the German Emperor]., 1908 April (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 41)
- [John Bull saying that he is the master of all other countries]., 1908 January (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 42)
- [John Bull distributing the goods of Egypt to the Egyptian people and the Europeans, appeared in The Cairo Punch]., 1908 April 17 (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 43)
- [John Bull placing leeches Egypt, appeared in The Cairo Punch]., 1908 January (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 44)
- [Germany addressing different countries]., 1908 August (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 45)
- [John bull acting as a shepherd to other countries depicted as sheep]., 1908 July (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 46)